realitieswatch.com 2017-04-15

# Privacy Policy & Disclaimer - Realities Watch

## **Our Commitment To Privacy**

Nothing is more important to the owners and staff of Realities Watch than the protection of our users privacy. This notice explains our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

## **The Information We Collect**

This notice applies to all information collected or submitted on the Websites. On some pages, you can specify personal profiles that may be viewable by other registered members of the Website. However, at no time do we collect your personal information such as name, address, or phone number, and we only require a functioning e-mail address for membership which will never be made publicly available. At no time do we attempt to reconcile any information you provide (including your IP address as indicated below) with offline identity or other personal information.

## **The Way We Use Information**

We use the information you provided about yourself only to credit users who submit content to the website. We also record the IP address you’re using at the time of each posted messages in order to enhance website security and monitor site traffic.

Your e-mail address is not used for any additional purpose other than registration for the Website and/or email newsletter and will never be shared with outside parties and is not viewable by unregistered members.

The non-identifying aggregate information is not stored on any server owned by the Websites as we do not collect or store any log files of activity on our websites. Instead, we employ Google Analytics (which does set a cookie) to obtain traffic analysis data.

Finally, we never use or share the personally identifiable information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above. Your profile information is protected from web-spiders that search for e-mail addresses and other personal information. We reserve the right to disclose any personally identifiable information associated with your account and/or posting history as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a court order or legal process served on Realities Watch.

## **Voluntary Input Of Personally Identifiable Information**

You should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of this site and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums and services, and may, at our discretion, remove any personally identifiable information you submit that appears in public view should it risk prejudicing the integrity or legality of the website.

## **Cookies**

From time to time data cookies will be set. At no time is any personally identifying information (other than website username) ever stored in these cookies. The cookies are used to provide our application with page-to-page awareness of your user status and/or access privileges. Most of these cookies expire within days, but some may expire in months or years.

## **Third Party Cookies**

Advertising networks that serve advertising on the Websites may write their own cookies for the purposes of determining advertising frequency and relevance, and to match ads against your interests based on aggregate non-personally identifiable information learned about your Internet browsing. We have performed reasonable diligence on all advertising networks authorised to serve ads on our websites to ensure that their data cookies are for this purpose and nothing more. Many of the providers serving display ads on the Websites provide users with the ability to [opt-out](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/html/opt-out.html) of these third-party cookies. Below is a non-exhaustive list of the networks which may, from time to time, deliver ads to our users (many may only occasionally deliver ads). For more information about these and other companies, and your options for restricting the use of your data, visit [Google Adsense](http://www.google.co.uk/policies/technologies/ads/), [Google Analytics](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en_uk/analytics/privacyoverview.html), [Tynt](http://www.tynt.com/privacy_policy.php), [content.ad](https://www.content.ad/privacy.aspx) and [WordPress](http://codex.wordpress.org/WordPress_Cookies).

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

## **Data Mining**

At no time will your personal profile information, posting history, or any other activity specific to your time on our websites be used for the purposes of targeted messages from advertisers or marketers purchasing ads or other marketing products on these websites.

## **Affiliate Relationships and Service Providers**

Certain partner websites may provide additional content or features, such as links to social networking websites which may display your public information if you sign in with these sites in order to comment or contribute. You should be aware that these are separate companies with privacy policies that may be different from ours. At no time is your personal information from the Websites provided to such sites, and we do not collect data from them that correlates to your member account.

## **Our Commitment To Data Security**

To prevent unauthorised access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

## **Our Commitment To The Protection Of Children**

Protecting the privacy of the young is especially important. For this reason, we never collect or maintain information at our website from those we actually know are under 13, and no part of our website is structured to attract anyone under 13.

## **Our Commitment Communication Privacy**

Members are provided with a private messaging system as part of their account privileges. Every reasonable effort is made to ensure the private messaging system is maintained in a secure fashion so as to ensure the privacy of any and all messages sent between members. Staff and/or owners will not observe the content or flow of any private messaging unless explicit reports of violations of the Terms and Conditions of Use or the Terms and Conditions of Membership are received.

## **Changes To This Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

## **Disclaimer**

This site may contain graphic content, images and/or discussions relating to illegal activities. Realities Watch in no way endorses this content or activity, and merely serves as a forum for the free discussion of such material. We reserve the right to remove any user-submitted content which may jeopardise the integrity or legality of the website and to take appropriate action against any users involved.

## **How To Contact Us**

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please do not hesitate to send us an email using our Contact Form.
